meet Isaac commonly known as the
sourcing guy on social media where his
videos have racked up millions of views
Isaac has become the go-to expert for
e-commerce entrepreneurs looking to
Source Products and he manages his
entire operation from barley his journey
started with selling portable fans to
sority girls at parties now he's
sourcing products for some of the
world's largest e-commerce Brands by
senior year we were already doing a few
million dollars in Wells in this video
Isaac shares how much he earns from his
business how beginners can start a
sourcing Venture and offers valuable
tips on finding the best products for
your e-commerce store when did you move
to Bali uh it's been 2 and a half years
now yeah and where did you move from
from Miami that is a big change right
it's a big change and a lot of people
ask me they're like what you're from
Miami like why would you ever leave
Miami and I do love Miami and like I'm
back like 3 four months out of the year
but you don't get this in Miami did you
just visit Bali for a holiday and she's
like this is it pretty much I mean I
kind of knew I wanted to go and live in
Asia and I was I was on a big sourcing
trip so I was visiting factories in
Cambodia Sri Lanka and Thailand yeah and
I was kind of burnt out after that and I
went heard B was this you know amazing
place to go and work from so I came out
here to come try it out and immediately
after like 3 days was like okay I can
actually see myself living here so what
were you doing before sourcing I've
always been sourcing so my dad when he
was my age moved to China and opened up
an Electronics Factory and then before
that my grandpa and my mom side we had a
small apparel Factory in Canada where I
was originally like born and grew up and
then would always go and work for the
factor from like being like a toddler
helping out with the Fabrics doing
Swatch cards and then when I was older
going to China with my dad helping
manage the factory there and then
decided rather start an agency to help
other people Source Products and become
like a sourcing agent and so I started
my agency eight years ago now I started
the business freshman year of college by
accident I brought these little cell
phone I would always like order gadgets
on AliExpress I thought they were fun I
brought this little cell phone fan that
plugs into your phone to a party just
cuz it was genuinely hot in Gainesville
Florida University of Florida and um I
go and I you know start using it at the
party and all these girls start coming
up to me like oh my God where do you get
that that's so cool I need that for
sority Rush and I kept on giving them
some of them like ala link or that Ali
Express link and then like the fifth
person they were like where do you get
that and I was like I'm I was kind of
drunk I was like I'm Isaac the fan guy I
sell fans they're $5 would you like one
and they're like yeah I'm like well I'm
sold out right now just completely like
off rip then I ordered the 100 sold down
a week and it wasn't the was it the you
were just slinging fans this is just me
this is like freshman year at College me
just slinging fans but then very quickly
bought 100 bought a thousand had people
sign them all around campuses had some
news articles about us then my hometown
reached out and they're like hey can we
buy 2,000 fans with our logo on them I'm
like yeah sure you know they'll be 20%
off but we made like $6,000 just off
that little bulk order and I was like
wait this is a way better business than
selling to drunk stor girls like I
should be selling these to businesses
this is a fun part about Bal you can
come in G makes my clothes oh really
yeah okay so one of the benefits about
Bali is that we have lots of access to
you know fabric markets and we have like
awesome tailor this is the issue with
like manufacturing and Bali it's an
island so you're not going to have all
these big fabric mills to be able to go
and get your the Fabrics a lot of them
are going to come from China either way
you're going to have uh from like a
labor cost perspective it's going to be
naturally higher than almost anywhere
else in Indonesia because it is like a
touristy kind of Zone and you have lots
of holidays and so like all these
different elements make it a very slow
expensive place that makes it hard to
scale but the thing is great brands have
started here yeah of course because they
have people like GE to be able to go and
they test out fabrics and they're able
to do small runs and get going um but
I'm helping like eight of my friends
right now with brand and Bali move their
manufacturing outside move mostly to
China because it's just it's too hard to
scale this is David he uh does all my
video work yeah so you has been growing
hates fast is H hey is that how you get
all your clients yeah exactly for the
most part we have some other like we
have sales reps and stuff like that yeah
but you know obviously you know the best
is inbound so we're making a series
about popular products and then how much
they actually cost we were having a hard
time in the beginning going to socials
because it was very education focused if
I don't make the videos that are
interesting to everyone I'm never going
to get the eyeballs and never be able to
actually grow my personal brand so it
took us a while of trial and error to
find the types of content that was going
to work yeah uh and then once we found
the series that worked we just kept on
repeating and now we're doing a lot more
travel stuff going over to Vietnam going
over to China doing more YouTube long
form last month we grew like 120,000
followers uh fully organic that's crazy
yeah and how many clients would you get
from that 300 inquiries a month probably
for sourcing and we'll take on like one
to two and what's that life the lifetime
value of the clients oh I mean a lot of
them are going to be six figures yeah so
it's crazy assing hundreds of thousands
just a off social media yeah it's it's
great awesome these are our sugar
gliders no way they don't look
real they're so cute they're super
cute so if you were starting out how
would you get your first s and classs so
I found like we started out uh doing
corporate sourcing so we were doing like
custom t-shirts custom water Bots hats
cuz you know most businesses are going
to need some level of like swag and
giveaways and that's a pretty low you
know low hanging fruit it's lower volume
it's going to get you kind of
comfortable going and sourcing products
and delivering the customers uh and you
kind of just grow from there you start
working with bigger and bigger
businesses you work on uh like getting
all those deliverables in place and then
the bigger jump is then working with
actual e-commerce Brands yeah uh and I
took it took us a few years of like
getting really comfortable with working
with factors overseas with overall
production process making sure
everything was perfect and then we can
start taking on you know seven plus
figure Ecom so you basically have to
find factories vet them make sure that
good and then put the clients in look is
that basically what you do that's what
we like to do so our whole thing is that
we've been curating the best factors
around the world because it's it's
pretty easy for Brands to go and find
like mediocre products you can go on
Alibaba you can filter you can find like
a decent product but if you want to find
like the best t-shirts in the world the
best hats the best of whatever the
product is that's the hard part but then
once you go and do all that work to find
the best of the best then you can bring
on a client and then easily go and plug
and play how do you charge that to a
customer because obviously they can
eventually find those factories it just
takes trial and error you're just saving
them time right and helping them manage
that relationship exactly we're saving
them time and reducing their risk
because a big obviously it's not just
the cost of the product but it's also
the risk that you might take by doing it
wrong so if you do a production run for
$100,000 and the production's wrong then
you have to you know not only do you
lose all the time yeah and the market
opportunity of selling the product
especially if your Brand's growing
really quickly but now you're going to
lose the actual product that's was
supposed to be blue and came out green
so could a beginner just G Alibaba find
a couple of factories organize the
samples and stuff like that or do you
need to actually go to China you build
the relationships again I think that a
beginner can go and make mediocre
products but if you want to make the
best product in the world that's where
the kind of experience and then the
whole kind of blueprint that we built
like that's where you have to go and
follow to really execute it's funny like
you and Daniel like you guys are
exploding on social media it's almost
like sourcing is becoming sexy like it's
always like cool now like finally the
most boring thing
well it was my like least favorite part
of like managing the Eon PR like why do
you think it's getting so beig I think
people are interested in like where
products are coming from right they love
behind the scenes especially with Tik
Tok and social media people want to see
like the get ready with me the behind
the scenes of The Olympian you know at
the Olympic Village eating their muffins
and all that kind of stuff social media
infection point I think so yeah and then
it's kind of a perfect uh Cross Point
because everyone wants to start a
business everyone wants to have a brand
right and they don't know how to do it
and then you also have the behind the
scenes of how these bigger brands are
manufacturing and where they're getting
their products from it makes it feel
very tangible yeah you know I I can do
this to relable relatable right it's
just like they see us selling your
product for $80 and they're like how
they even making this possible seeing it
be made for $10 and just like wow I'm
actually going to be able to do this
exactly what your main tips of dealing
with like China and the supplies there
you want to keep them on their toes as
much as possible so a lot of people go
and they think like oh I have my Factory
in China I'm good with them I don't I
don't really need a backup and I'm
scared to let my factory or my agent
know that I'm looking at other factories
because it's going to hurt the
relationship my opinion it's only going
to strengthen the relationship because
if they know that they can take
advantage then they probably will so you
H them knowing that you have
contingencies you have other factors
you're negotiating with you're showing
them the pricing you're getting from
other factories they know that if they
don't you know act as an a level
supplier someone else you know it's a
very competitive game someone else is
going to take the business so I would
say always have that back up and then
from a production standpoint you really
really have to like that's why we built
like like an 80 step process to go and
Source Products and the team has to go
through and check off like 80 boxes
because there's so many little ways
where you can mess up but if you follow
the steps like you will not mess up one
of the biggest things is is clear
communication so can you build a
specification sheet can you build a tech
pack can you build exactly how the
product is going to look exactly how
you're going to imprint it something I
like to talk about is centering just
because you tell the factory this is
centered doesn't mean they're going to
center it properly they're not really
going to is is it centered this way is
it centered this way it's better to go I
want 4 in here 4 Ines here 2 Ines here 2
Ines here then say centered so again as
specific as you can go don't let them
make any decisions for you try to make
them all what techs are tell me about
the progression of the agencies like
first year what did you make second year
what did you make what was like the
major turning point yeah I mean so
started off in college doing like you
know few 100K just going and selling
some merchandise by the time you know
graduated in college but by senior year
we were already you know doing a few
million dollars in sales so it was a big
growth a lot of that came from starting
to work with more e-commerce clients
yeah so what happened was we started in
corporate and the corporate business was
great it was really fun but we were
doing everything direct to factory we
had a different model of how we were
sourcing the merchandise because all my
friends kind of you get it like when
you're a young entrepreneur and you you
know have a cool business who are the
other ones in their 20s it's normally
the Ecom guys so a lot of my friends are
these Ecom guys and then Co hits all
their supply chains break right but
their sales are growing because ads are
performing so they're like they call me
and they're like Isaac can you go in can
you help me here so I'm like yeah sure
and then we went and started taking on
these like huge projects taking over
company's entire Supply chains and it
really was like a test because it was
the hardest time to ever source and ship
product but we were able to do it
successfully So Co it also accelerated
demand but of the complexity it got your
hate to CL they realize how fragile
their supply chain exactly and I think
that it's still at this point where
Brands now know that they need to have
contingencies and we're coming in and
we're building out those contingencies
for them yeah so what year was that that
yeah was your third year of the agency
that was my yeah my third year of the
agency third or fourth year I like my
agency what we're trying to do is we're
trying to again offer more solutions for
smaller Brands because I mean you get it
like the impact that we can make is
going to be very much tied to like the
overall scale yeah also a lot of what we
do is move stuff out of China Cambodia
Sri Lanka Vietnam Thailand we're going
to um a little bit of Northern Africa so
Egypt has been great uh we're doing some
stuff in Pakistan it's really like an an
observation of you have to look at where
the raw material is coming from you have
to look at the labor cost you have to
look at overall taxes and you know where
that kind of country is progressing so
you can kind of run onun a little bit of
analysis and look at the volumes and say
okay like if you go and you move over to
Egypt your lead time is going to you
know increase by 30% but your cost basis
is going to decrease by 30 so what's
worth it I think it's the cost basis
what's the kind of good first year in
terms of income creating like a sourcing
agency I think you could off of first
year you could make like probably 60
Grand pretty easily if you go to any
like decent sized business they're
probably going and they're spending $100
$200,000 on like t-shirts and mugs and
those kinds of products if you're able
to run a 50% margin all you really need
to do is get $120,000 in sales get
majority of one business's book of
business and you can make like you know
a decent salary how do you get that
first client should like obviously it's
corporate as you said do you just DM
them or do you like Source their product
cheaper like so well I think that
sourcing going with price isn't how I
love to sell but I think when you're
getting started it's the best way
the whole thing with the corporate
merchandise is that majority of people
don't Factory Direct they're going
through these this domestic supplier
networks so these big suppliers in the
industry that go and they're going to
stock you know millions of t-shirts
millions of water Bots millions of hats
and then the domestic industry you just
go and you submit a purchase order to a
warehouse in the US they decorate the
product and they deliver it to your
client for you but if you're if you go
direct to factory you can easily get
like 30% less yeah so all you need to do
is go to any business i' recommend going
in your local area so you can go door
knocking you can go up to them and say
like hey you know we're different we
Source merchandise for brand but we're
different because we're going Factory
Direct so we typically can get pricing
for way cheaper can you just go and tell
me the products that you're going and
and making right now and let me price it
out for you right and then they're going
to go and they're going to say yeah for
the hats you're paying $12 and then
you're going to go on alib Baba and
you're going to go and you're going to
find a hat for $3 and then you can go
and sell to them for seven would you go
get a sample from that factory like
let's say we've got the udy on a hat
yeah do you need the actual sample from
the company first to then send to the
supplier to get the actual final sample
or you just like these are my actual
prices and you can just do it without
touching into so I always recommend
trying to get samples from factories if
you never worked with them before
because you don't want to go and pitch a
product that's going to be low quality
um you want to send reference samples of
if the clients very happy so if the
client's like I love this hat it's
perfect it's just too expensive great
take that sample ship it over to China
um and have the factory go and try to
replicate it the best they can what's a
really really good sourcing agency like
make how much cash can they produce I
mean I know sourcing agencies that do
hundreds of millions of dollars in sales
a year wow I mean like yeah I know
people with sourcing agencies that have
$80 million houses in Hong Kong you know
incredible so you can make a ton of
money I met a guy in Hong Kong recently
and he started like at my age pretty
much just going to China starting to
sling products he was growing the
sourcing agency eventually got to the
point where you started buying minority
Stakes into some like headwear factories
and started really uh focusing on that
category then close you know like people
like New Era as clients so you start
going after really really big business
there's kind of two ways you can go with
it you can either resell the product and
have your margin baked into it or you
can have a flat percentage basis and
then make the money off of all the
production that you're managing so he
kept on growing growing getting bigger
and bigger clients really understanding
Niche having the best pricing out there
at the point for this quality of hat and
then built it built it built it into
doing you know he does hundreds of
hundreds of millions of dollars a year
now that's crazy what's the main thing
when you buy a factory that you need to
know or buy interest in a factory it's a
tricky thing it's it's something I don't
recommend you just start out like okay
this what I'm going to do I'm going
start buying a factory because most
people that I know that Bond factories
have failed miserably and have burned
themselves pretty significantly unless
you're going to go and live there at the
factory and I going to be able to do
things that times samples getting
created like was the main I would say
pricing and also quality uh so like for
example my dad the benefit of him having
the factory in China was to be able to
produce the highest quality power
inverters in the world so that he could
get the licenses for the big Brands and
and really offer you know a product that
wasn't available in the market so he
really focused on engineering and R&D uh
and that was his main stress was that he
kept on going to China he had an
e-commerce brand uh he was selling these
inverters and he kept on going to China
and was really stressed out because he
could never get the quality that he
wanted to in the market so we just said
screw it I'm just going to make open up
my own Factory and make sure the quality
is perfect yeah that's incredible well
man you know your very uh very
happy to have you own daily menoy your
guidance has been crazy for for all of
these uh Brands as well so I appreciate
yeah of course man it's been a pleasure
ch